NADZEYA SHEDAVA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

469.226.0262

nadejdashed@gmail.com

Seattle, WA

EDUCATION

BACHELOR | 2012

Belarusian State University of Informatics and Radioelectronics, Minsk, Belarus

Software Engineer

TECHINAL SKILLS

EXPERT

Javascript / Typescript

Angular

Html & Css

Bootstrap / Material

Git

PROFICIENT

Java

Spring

React / React Native

Node.js

Karma / Jasmine

Protractor

Sass

SQL

Docker

AWS

PROFILE

Lead Software Engineer with 10 years of experience focused on design, development, and delivery of client-server web applications. Able to apply critical thinking to everyday tasks and look at the product from an end-user perspective. Eager and willing to learn new skills, but at the same time, passionate about the success of others and actively provides support for team development. Preferable roles on the project: Full Stack Developer / Team Lead.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

AstrumU / May 2021 - Till Now

Web applications to help translate educational experiences into economic opportunity.

- Quick onboarding in three different projects completed the first feature contribution during the first month.
- Took full responsibility on Metric Dashboard MVP, the goal of which is to increase sales.

KEY FULL STACK DEVELOPER / TECH LEAD

EPAM / US based delivery services company / May 2020 - Mar 2021

A new web application to manage customer organization standards.

- Initiated a core structure of a new Angular application.
- Completed a large portion of a REST Spring application.
- Implemented a scheduled Spring Batch ETL job for data migration.
- Set up a development process baseline: CI/CD (static analysis, unit & automated testing, deployment), documentation.
- Collaborated with business & technical stakeholders and translated requirements to low-level design.
- Mentored the customer team for Frontend (FE) technologies and development best practices.

KEY FRONTEND DEVELOPER

EPAM / Independent oil & gas exploration & production company / Jul 2019 - Mar 2020

Implementation of shared Angular UX/UI libraries across the organization.

- Cyctopoisted the list of required showed company and the decision to an
- Systemized the list of required shared components with the design team.
 Implemented shared components: breadcrumbs, tabs, topbar, menu, notifications.
- Implemented crucial business requests: integration with ApplicationInsights, setup user behavior analytics, IE 11 support.
- Added component testing to the existing Microsoft Azure DevOps pipeline.

KEY FRONTEND DEVELOPER / DEVELOPMENT TEAM LEAD

EPAM / American data analytics and risk assessment firm / Dec 2016 - Jun 2019

Insurance document management solution with intelligent search, document analysis, and reporting capabilities.

- Refactored an existing AngularJS application to increase maintainability and reusability.
- Decreased number of defects from more than 100 to about 20.
- Mentored the FE and Full Stack developers; provided FE courses across the whole team.
 Implemented a critical business feature to present document comparison using SVG.
- Developed a library of shared Angular 6 components and services.
- Started migration the AngularJS application to Angular 6.
 Migrated FE of another legacy application to a new tech stack (Angular 6 + AWS).

KEY FRONTEND DEVELOPER

EPAM / Oilfield services company / Sep 2016 - Feb 2017

Visualization of a drilling process as part of a more extensive Angular application.

KEY FULL STACK DEVELOPER / DEVELOPMENT TEAM LEAD

EPAM / Flag carrier airline company / Mar 2014 - Sep 2016

The company's official site to book flights, manage trips and do check-in.

- Was the primary focal point for questions in the FE competency area.
- Led a team of 8 FE engineers responsible for the development and partial support of the main site.
- Helped 3 team members to mature from Junior Software Engineers to Senior level.
 Established a core structure for all pow projects: Discovery (Angular 15), administra
- Established a core structure for all new projects: Discovery (Angular JS), administration tool (Angular JS + Node.js).

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

EPAM / Multinational hospitality company / Jan 2014 - Feb 2014

A cross-platform Sencha Touch application for hotel administration by hotel personal and management.

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

EPAM / Enterprise information management software company / Oct 2012 - Dec 2013

Business processes & document management web application with an extensive rules engine.

KEY FRONTEND DEVELOPER

EPAM / Multinational computer technology corporation / Jun 2012 - Sep 2012

Implementation of mobile web part of large Web Commerce Platform.

JUNIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER

EPAM / Technology services company for digital transformation / Aug 2011 - May 2012

Development of XSLT transformations from a desktop version of web applications to mobile.

ADDITIONAL

KEY FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Belarus' Solidarity / Nov 2020 - Till Now

Volunteering development of a mobile donation application on React Native for people of Belarus affected by government repression.